[Music]
welcome back you're still watching
business lunch on cnbc tv 18 there has
been a little bit more of a slip in the
market the mid cap index has also
slipped into the red now so we're around
two tenths of a percent low and you can
see quite a sharp fall coming through
over there but let's talk stocks now
general insurance data for the month of
august has been released and we have
yash joining us with the roundup of the
numbers it's looking quite good this
month actually
well the general insurance industry has
seen a strong growth in its premium
collection in the month of august but
unfortunately the same can't be said for
the two listed companies out of the
sector i'll first start talking about
the industry itself for the general
insurance sector including standalone
health insurance as well as standard
insurance both the industry has seen a
growth of about 24 in the month of
august in its premium collection on a
year-on-year basis but that premium
collection is down by about 35 when
compared to an average of the first four
months of fi 22. for the general
insurance industry if standalone health
insurance is excluded then the premium
has grown by about 18 in the month of
august on a year-on-year basis and about
11 percent when compared to an average
of the first four months of fi 22. the
standalone health insurance sector is
something that has seen the strongest
growth in the month of august growing at
about 26
on a year on your comparison but it's
down about 8 when compared to an average
of the first four months of fi 22.
speaking about the two listed companies
for icici lombard it's a it's a miss
from top to bottom the total premium
collection in the month of august is up
just by about a percent and a half on a
year on your basis it's down three
percent when compared to an average of
the first four months of fi 22 and also
there's a market share loss of about 44
basis points year to month as far as the
company is concerned for new india
assurance uh the the performance is
slightly better as compared to icsa
lombard the premium is up 30 in the
month of august on a year on your basis
it's down 21 when compared to the first
four months of fi 22 but on the positive
side there's a market share gain of
about 1.7
uh year to month for the company as far
as august is concerned
all right uh thanks so much yash for
giving us all those details moving on
then despite liquor shops being shot for
months owing to central and the state
government lockdowns well the state of
tamil nadu consumed more alcohol in fy
21 than ever before and this is
according to a report released by the
tamil nadu state marketing corporation
or tasmac which holds remember the
monopoly over alcohol retail in that
state and cnbc tv 18's jude sanet joins
us to bring us up to speed with the
latest so jude tasman they're recording
its highest ever revenue in the 18 years
it's been around what's the number like
and what's the sense you're getting
about high spirits in the state
well in fy 21 alone these task mark
outlets run of course by the tamil nadu
state marketing corporation have
recorded a whopping revenue of thirty
three thousand eight hundred and eleven
crore rupees now this remember is
tasman's highest revenue collection ever
since the company was constituted in
2003 to monopolize sales of alcohol
across the state of tamil nadu and it's
also a two percent spike over the 33 133
crore rupees by way of sales task mark
generated in fy 20. now more
significantly this comes even as these
task mark outlets were shut between
april and june last year over to the
nationwide lockdown and also for four to
five weeks earlier this year thanks to
the kovitz second wave um this year has
been no different in fact task mark has
already recorded sales of 7900 odd crore
rupees up until july 2021 as far as
fiscal year or fy 2020 fy 22 is
concerned and what we're also given to
understand that this good performance
means that employees of task mark
outlets have also been handed a need
increment of anywhere between 500 to 25
000 rupees by way of their salaries
itself so taskmark doing well even as it
runs close to 5400
outlets across the state and 2 800 bars
so what can we say the pandemic means
more people seem to be enjoying that
that drink even as tough times are upon
us
that's right tough times jude you said
it and tough times looks like uh for the
telecom space because uh the details
that we're getting from sources is that
there is no decision taken by the
cabinet on the telecom relief package
and that could be having a bearing
especially on vodafone idea and that
stock is knocked down at the moment
because of the shattering of hopes of
any relief package coming in today but
we'll also keep an eye out on the
lenders to vodafone idea from the
banking space for vitra
all right nisha thanks a lot for
bringing us up to speed on that but
moving on now recoveries under the
insolvency and bankruptcy code continue
to decline the latest data from the
insolvency and bankruptcy board of india
shows that cumulative recovery is down
to 36 percent as of june from about 40
that we saw in the previous quarter but
does the law still remain the best tool
in the hands of banks ritu singh is here
with a report card of the bankruptcy law
five years after it came into effect
the insolvency and bankruptcy code was
hailed as a game changer for the bad
loan resolution landscape in india and
it is now in its fifth year so let's
look at data from the insolvency and
bankruptcy board of india to see what
has happened so far now there were 4
541 cases that were admitted into the
nclt so far about 63 percent have been
closed and 38 are still ongoing now of
these only 14 percent of found
resolution and almost half have actually
ended up in liquidation but when we're
talking about that it is very important
to note that 75 of the companies that
ended up in liquidation were already
sick or defunct so the chances of their
recovery even under ibc was very low to
begin with and now how many new cases
have been added 126 in the last quarter
ending june uh about 533 between f5 20
and 21 uh which is the year when ibc
remained in suspension which is why this
number looks lower now there have been
some recent instances of large haircuts
by lenders like in the case of jet and
videocon which have cast a shadow on the
recovery under ibc so let's also look at
that data now recovery by financial
creditors under the court that fell to
about 36 percent as of the quarter
ending june and this is a cumulative
number compared to a little over 39 in
the previous quarter it is still higher
than the same period last year but lower
than the pre-covert levels of about 45
but does ibc still remain the best tool
for recovery is a question we're asking
and it certainly seems so when you
compare it with the other tools of
resolution like the drt or the surface
the other big area of concern has been
the long delays in what was supposed to
be a time-bound resolution process above
all else and here's what data says 75 of
the ongoing cases have already exceeded
270 days and the ones that have been
resolved took more than 400 days on
average versus a maximum period of 330
days prescribed by law so yes while
there's a lot left to be desired when it
comes to ibc experts still believe that
it has put control back in the hands of
lenders and improved credit discipline
it also continues to evolve this is only
a five-year-old law at the end of the
day but with all said and done it
remains the best tool that banks
currently have
all right thanks ritu for that and on
that note we'll slip into a short
breather on business lunch but before we
do that we'll get you the most exciting
announcement for you our viewers get
money control pro at just one rupee per
day and get a chance to win daily prizes
worth 50 000 rupees and a mega prize of
macbook pro log logged onto money
control today limited period offer
[Music]
you